export default  English_Ministry_2015 = [
  {
    id: "h1",
    Number_of_Questions: "60 Questions",
    Time_Allowed: "1 hour",
  },
  {
    id: 'h2',
    header1: "Grade 8 English Ministry Exam 2015/2023"
  },
  {
    id: "I",
    header1: "I. Comprehension \n Part One: Reading Passage",
    header2: "Instruction: For items 1-7, read the following passage and answer the questions according to the information given in the passage.",
    // options: ["The bat", "The flying squirrel", "The bald eagle", "The colugo"],
    // correct_option: "The bat"
  },
  { 
    id: 'p1',
       passage: " Friendship is something that everyone needs in life, regardless of age, background, or achievements. It can be defined as a relationship between two or more people who care about one another and share similarities. People often make bonds with those they share common interests with, or those they view as being friends. Despite the many kinds of friendship out there - some temporary, some lifelong - it always involves loyalty and trust." +
" The type of friendship varies depending on the situation. For some, a friendship formed in childhood may last until adulthood Others might have numerous friends of different ages, some an entire life and others just a few months old while still maintaining the same level of closeness with all of them. Professional connections can also be considered friendships if those involved remain loyal to each other and trust each other's judgment." +
" Spending time together is important for any kind of relationship to thrive - that includes friendships too! Having conversations helps build your bond with someone as you reach greater understanding through shared experiences, values, needs, worries, dreams and visions for the future. Simple activities like playing games together, watching movies or going shopping make time spent together even more meaningful by creating lasting moments you love to look back on fondly." +
" Having meaningful friendships doesn't only bring color and purpose into our lives; it also helps us become better versions of ourselves. Your friends can inspire you to do great things in life and provide unconditional support when you need it most during tough times. Ultimately, no matter what stage your friendship is in whether brand new or lifelong- it provides a kind of safety net that should never be taken for granted!" +
"Adapted from Advance with English 3."

  },
  
  {
    id: 1,
    question: "What does 'Friendship' mean?",
    options: ["A connection between two people who care about each other",
 "An agreement between two business partners", "Relocating from one place to another ", "Making differences with others"],
    correct_option: "A connection between two people who care about each other"
  },
  {
    id: 2,
    question: "How can spending time together strengthen friendships? ",
    options: ["By talking about similar interests","By watching movies together"," By relying on one another financially "," By competing against each other"],
    correct_option: "By watching movies together"
  },
  {
    id: 3,
    question: "What do long-lasting friendships require ",
    options: ["Shared stories and secrets", "Mutual commitment and loyalty ", "Time management skills", " Financial support"],
    correct_option: "Mutual commitment and loyalty "
  },
  {
    id: 4,
    question: "What are the benefits of having close friends?",
    options: ["Relieving stress.", "Gaining new skills.","Professional development.", "Improved self-confidence."],
    correct_option: "Relieving stress."
  },
  {
    id: 5,
    question: ' What does the pronoun "it" (paragraph 1 line 2) refers to ',
    options: ["Age", " Background", "Friendship", " Achievements "],
    correct_option: "Friendship "
  },
  
  {
    id: 6,
    question: 'The word "thrive" in paragraph 3 line 1 means:',
    options: [" fail", "disaster", "diversify", "succeed"],
    correct_option: "succeed"
  },
  {
    id: 7,
    question: 'The word "fondly" in paragraph 3 line 6 means:',
    options: ["lovingly", "kindly", "carelessly", "unhappily"],
    correct_option: "lovingly "
  },
{ 
    id: "II.1",
    header1: "Sentence Comprehension",
    header2: "Instruction One: For items 8 and 9 choose the alternative that has the same or nearly the same meaning as the original sentence.",
  },
    
  {
    id: 8,
    question: " Either of the students passed the exam.",
    options: ["Both the students passed the exam.", "Neither of the students passed the exam.", "Only one of the students passed the exam.", "Monkeysâ€™ blackish-brown hands, feet, and ears"],
    correct_option: "Only one of the students passed the exam.",
    explanation:`"Either--or" is a correlative conjunction used to present alternatives or choices between two possibilities.\n`+
    ` It indicates that one of the options presented is true, but not both.\n`+
    `For example, in the sentence "You can either come with me to the movies or stay home," the speaker is presenting two options: coming to the movies or staying home, implying that the listener must choose one option but cannot do both simultaneously.`
    
  },
  {
    id: 9,
    question:"My son is too short to open the window.",
    options: ["My son opens the window because he is very short", " My son is not tall enough to open the window", "My son opens the window although he is very short", " My shortest son opens the window."],
    correct_option: "My son is not tall enough to open the window",
    explanation:`The sentence "My son is not tall enough to open the window" suggests that the speaker's son lacks the necessary height to reach and operate the window.`
       },
  { 
      id: "II",
      header1: "Section Three: Vocabulary \n Part One: Substitution",
      header2: "Instruction: for items 10-14, choose the most suitable alternative meaning for the words written in bold in the sentences.",
    },

  {
    id: 10,
    question: ' This machine is "labor-intensive", it is operated with hands.',
    options: ["electricity", "manual", "  independent ", "  automatic "],
    correct_option: "manual",
    explanation:'The phrase "labor-intensive" typically implies that a task or process requires a significant amount of human effort or manual work.'
  },

  {
    id: 11,
    question: `All the species of dinosaurs are "nonexistent". We can't even find one.`,
    options: ["existed", "extinct", "  appeared", "  happened"],
    correct_option: "extinct ",
    explanation:`The word "nonexistent" suggests that all species of dinosaurs are no longer present or alive today. This indicates that they are no longer part of the Earth's fauna and have disappeared from the planet. Therefore, the term that best fits the context and meaning of the sentence is "extinct."`
  },
  {
    id: 12,
    question: ` She wanted to study the culture of the Borena People. So, she went and met the "indigenous" people there.`,
    options: ["foreign ", " external ", "native", " outside"],
    correct_option: "native",
    explanation:`In the context provided, the word "indigenous" refers to the original or native inhabitants of the area. Therefore, the most suitable option to complete the sentence is:"native"`
  },

  {
    id: 13,
    question: `All my friends are the same but Simegn is very "special", that is why I love her most`,
    options: ['unique', ' alike ', ' similar', ' parallel '],
    correct_option: "unique",
    explanation: `In the given context, the word "special" suggests that Simegn possesses qualities or characteristics that distinguish her from the others, making her stand out. Therefore, the most appropriate option to complete the sentence is:"unique"`
  },

    {
    id: 14,
    question: `  Zewdu is responsible to "look after" the cows in the family because he is the youngest child in the family`,
    options: ["follow", "take after",     "take care", " tail "],
    correct_option: "take care",
    explanation:`In the given context, "look after" indicates the responsibility of Zewdu to take care of the cows in the family. `
  },
  { 
      id: "III",
      header1: "Part Two: Completion",
      header2: "Instruction: Questions 15-19 are incomplete. Choose the word that best completes each sentence meaningfully.",
    },

  {
    id: 15,
    question: " The expected behaviors of the students are mentioned in the rules and-of the",
    options: ["regulation", " books "," directors ", " moral"],
    correct_option: "regulation ",
    explanation:`The phrase "expected behaviors of the students" suggests that the sentence is discussing guidelines or instructions related to student conduct."+
    "Therefore, the most suitable option to complete the sentence is:"regulation"`
  },
  {
    id: 16,
    Question: "The car I bought is more _____ on fuel usage. It consumes 1 liter per 10 km.",
    Options: ["expensive", " cheap school.", " fast", "economical"],
    correct_option: "economical",
    explanation:`The sentence suggests that the car the speaker bought is efficient in terms of fuel usage, consuming only 1 liter per 10 kilometers."+
    "Therefore, the most suitable option to complete the sentence is:"economical"`
  },
  {
    id: 17,
    question: " Drinking lots of water helps to give you ______ skin. It helps you to have smooth and clear skin.",
    options: ["painful", "bad", "health", " dry"],
    correct_option: "healthy",
    explanation:`Given that drinking lots of water is associated with having smooth and clear skin, the most suitable option to complete the sentence is:"health"`
  },
  {
    id: 18,
    question: "Ethiopia was winning 3-2 until the last minute of the game when Sudan was able to score 1 and_____ ",
    options: ["equalize", " beat  ","  win ", " defeat"],
    correct_option: "equalize",
    explanation:`Given the context provided, where Ethiopia was winning 3-2 until Sudan scored a goal, the most suitable option to complete the sentence is:"equalize"`
  },
  {
    id: 19,
    question: "Alemayehu works for the company that ______ electrical goods like TV, computer,mobiles, etc ",
    options: ["harvest ", "  yield ", "  fruitage ", "produce"],
    correct_option: "produce",
    explanation:`Given the context provided, where Alemayehu works for a company that manufactures electrical goods like TVs, computers, and mobiles, the most suitable option to complete the sentence is:"produce"`
  },

  { 
      id: "IV",
      header2: "Instruction: Read the following passage carefully and answer questions 20.-29 accordings the information given in the passage." +
      " Values are a set of beliefs, ideas or codes that we live by in our everyday life. To put it simply, values direct us to what we think is desirable and important in how we live. Depending on the person and their cultural environment values can be heavily influenced by family, religion, education and external experiences. Values can change over time as people grow and experience new things." +
      " Different cultures have different values that shape the way people interact with one another and how they view certain concepts such as success or charity. For example some may value material wealth while others value spiritual growth. On an individual level values can be a source of personal recognition or strength when making ethical decisions in the face of difficult situations." +
      " In order for good decision making to occur, it is important that individuals define their own personal values and practice them in their daily life. Valuing yourself correctly can lead to better mental health and psychological wellbeing. Furthermore it also allows us to recognize what matters most so that we can make decisions that are in line with these idealistic visions of our lives." +
                    "Adapted from Skills Development for Active Reading",
    },

  {
    id: 20,
    question: "What is meant value",
    options: ["The official laws of a nation ", "  The customs of a particular culture","A set of beliefs, ideas or codes", "  Ideas laid down by religious texts"],
    correct_option: "A set of beliefs, ideas or codes",
      },
  {
    id: 21,
    question: "What factors often influence one's culture?",
    options: ["Ideas laid down by religious texts", " Food", "  External environment", " Nature"],
    correct_option: "Ideas laid down by religious texts",
      },

    {
    id: 22,
    Question: "How do values contribute to good decision-making?",
    options: ["By weighing ethical arguments "," By reflecting society's views"," By understanding legal guidelines "," By defining one's personal values "],
    correct_option: "By defining one's personal values",
    },
{
    id: 23,
    question: " If one valuing him/herself correctly, he/she will have",
    options: ["a better mental health"," an improved physical health"," a greater wealth"," an unclear vision"],
    correct_option: "a better mental health",
     },
{
    id: 24,
    question: "How can someone's values change over time?",
    options: ["Value ","Valuing yourself correctly"," good decision making"," greater wealth"],
    correct_option: "Valuing yourself correctly",
    },
{
    id: 25,
    question: " The people of the area cut lot of trees per day. This leads to __________ ",
    options: ["Afforestation ","replanting ","deforestation "," rainfall"],
    correct_option: "deforestation",
      },
{ 
  id: "V",
  header1: "Part II. Language Focus/ Grammar",
  header2: "Instruction: For item 26-43, choose the one that best completes each sentence.",
},


{
  id: 26,
  Question: "He cleans his office every day. This is the same as ",
  Options: ["his office is cleaned every day", "his office is cleaning every day"," his office cleans every day"," his office has cleaned every day"],
  correct_option: "his office is cleaned every day",
  explanation:`The sentence "He cleans his office every day" describes a routine action performed by someone (he) to clean their own office.`+ 
  "This is equivalent to the option: his office is cleaned every day"+
  "This option conveys the same meaning as the original sentence, indicating that the cleaning of his office occurs regularly every day."
    },
  {
  id: 27,
  question: "Abebe is________than his brother ",
  options: ["short","shorter","shortest","more short"],
  correct_option: "shorter",
  explanation:`The sentence "Abebe is shorter than his brother" is comparing the height of Abebe to that of his brother. When making a comparison of inequality between two things or people,`+ 
  ` the correct form to use for the comparative degree of short is "shorter."`
},
{
  id: 28,
  question: "She_____study harder because she will have a test tomorrow.",
  options: [" has  "," have ","should"," may "],
  correct_option: "should",
  explanation:`The word "should" is used to indicate a recommendation or advisability in this context. When someone has a test coming up, it is commonly understood that studying harder would be beneficial for their preparation.`
},
{
  id: 29,
  Question: "It was warm, so I ______ off my coat.",
  options: [" take","took","taked"," takes "],
  correct_option: "took",
  explanation: `The verb "took" is the past tense form of "take." In the sentence provided, "It was warm, so I took off my coat," the action of taking off the coat occurred in the past.`
},
{
  id: 30,
  question: "In his whole life time, Abel_____snake ",
  options: ["has never see","have never seen","has never seen","had never seen"],
  correct_option: "has never seen",
  explanation: `The sentence "In his whole lifetime, Abel has never seen a snake" is in the present perfect tense. The present perfect tense is used to indicate actions that started in the past and continue up to the present moment, or actions that have occurred at some indefinite time in the past.`
},
{
  id:31,
  question: "Our English teacher,_____lives around the school, is a very nice pesol.",
  options: ["who"," whose"," which "," that"],
  correct_option: "Who",
  explanation: `The word "who" is used to introduce a relative clause that provides additional information about the English teacher. In this context, the relative clause "who lives around the school" describes a characteristic or attribute of the English teacher.`
},
{
  id:32,
  question: "I________ take a bus to work but sometimes I take a taxi.",
  options: ["always"," seldom"," usually","sometimes"],
  correct_option: "usually",
  explanation:""
},
{
  id: 33,
  question: " Now, we have a baby to take care of so we _______ get the chance to go to the cinema.",
  options: ["always"," rarely","usually", "mostly "],
  correct_option: "rarely",
  explanation: `The word "rarely" is used to indicate that something happens infrequently or seldom.`
  },
{
  id:34,
  question: " If he _______ them, he will get their assistance",
  options: ["asked "," ask"," had asked ","asks"],
  correct_option: "asks",
  explanation: `The sentence "If he asks them, he will get their assistance" is a conditional statement.`+
  ` It presents a hypothetical situation where the condition is expressed using the present simple tense "asks".`
},
{
  id:35,
  question: "Most young drivers drive_________",
  options: ["fast"," fastly"," fastestiy"," fasterly "],
  correct_option: "fast",
  explanation: `The word "fast" is an adverb that describes how something is done.`+
  "In this case, it describes the manner in which most young drivers drive."
},
{
  id:36,
  question: "Every morning, the sun _____in my bedroom window and wakes me up",
  options: ["shining","had shined ","shines"," shined"],
  correct_option: "shines",
  explanation:"The sentence describes a habitual action that occurs regularly every morning. In English, when describing routines or habits, we often use the present simple tense."
},
{
  id:37,
  question: " I _______ get up early tomorrow. There are a lot of things I want to do. -Specific obligation",
  options: ["must","have to"," can"," could"],
  correct_option: "have to",
  explanation: `"have to" is commonly used to express specific obligations or requirements. When someone says "I have to [verb]," it means they are obligated to do that action due to external factors or personal commitments.`
},
{
  id: 38,
  question: "My uncle______ to the market and bought a lot of things yesterday",
  options: ["go","is going","gone","went"],
  correct_option: "went",
  explanation: `The sentence describes an action that occurred in the past (yesterday), so it requires the past tense form of the verb "go." "Went" is the past tense form of "go," which correctly conveys that the action of going to the market happened in the past.`
},
{
  id:39,
  question: " They were studying Mathematics. The question form of this statement is ",
  options: ["Did they study Mathematics?"," Do the study Mathematics? "," Were they studying Mathematics?"," Was they studying Mathematics"],
  correct_option: "Were they studying Mathematics?",
  explanation: ` The statement "They were studying Mathematics" is in the past continuous tense, indicating an action that was ongoing in the past.`+
      `  To form a question from a past continuous statement, the auxiliary verb "were" is moved to the beginning of the sentence, and the subject follows it.`+
      " This inversion of the subject and auxiliary verb is used to form questions in English."
},
{
  id:40,
  question: `The "noun" form of the verb "invent" is ___________`,
  options: ["inventment","invents","  invented","  invention"],
  correct_option: "invention",
  explanation:"The noun form of a verb is often created by adding a suffix or changing the ending to a form that denotes a person, thing, or action associated with the verb."+
  `In this case, the noun form of the verb "invent" is "invention."`
},

{
  id:41,
  question: "The 'adjective' form of the noun 'fitness' is________",
  options: ["fit","fitly","fitted","fits"],
  correct_option: "fit",
  explanation:"The adjective form of a noun typically describes qualities or characteristics of the noun."+
  "In this case, the noun 'fitness' refers to the state of being physically fit or healthy."+
  "Therefore, 'fit' is the correct adjective form of the noun 'fitness.'"
},
{
  id:42,
  question: " I was reading a book when he______â€™",
  options: ["arrived","  arrive"," arrives","arriving "],
  correct_option: "arrived",
  explanation:"The sentence 'I was reading a book when he arrived' is in the past continuous tense, indicating an ongoing action in the past ('I was reading') interrupted by another action ('he arrived')."
},
{
  id:43,
  question:  "Eden thinks that she should work hard in her education,______Abel also thinks he should focus on his study.",
  options: ["however"," but","hence","likewise"],
  correct_option: "likewise",
  explanation:"This option indicates agreement or similarity between the actions or thoughts of Eden and Abel. 'Likewise' means 'similarly' or 'in the same way,' making it the appropriate choice to show that Abel shares a similar belief or intention with Eden."
},
{ 
  id: "VI",
  header1: "Part III. Speaking",
  header2: "Instruction: For items 44-51, chose the one which best compels the remaining part of the dialogue given.",
},


{

  id:44,
  question: " Meron: Would you tell me what shall we do for our trip? \n Zinash:_________________",
  options: ["You should plan the whole journey before starting. "," You can't plan the whole journey before starting."," you may plan the whole journey before starting"," You may plan the whole journey before starting."],
  correct_option: "You should plan the whole journey before starting.",
  explanation:"This response suggests a recommendation or suggestion for Meron to plan the entire journey before they embark on their trip. It implies that thorough planning is important for a successful trip."
},
{
  id:45,
  question: "Ali:_________that your boss treats you like that. \n" + 
     " Melaku: Yes, it was unfair, but what can I do?",
  options: [" I am so happy","It makes me angry"," That is very nice"," I am so proud"],
  correct_option: "It makes me angry",
  explanation:`The phrase "It makes me angry" is an appropriate completion for Ali's statement because it reflects Ali's emotional response to the situation being discussed.`+
  "In this context, Ali is expressing his emotional reaction to the unfair treatment that Melaku received from his boss. "
},
{
  id:46,
  question: "Father: Every Family member should respect each other. \n Mother:_______?",
  options: [" I was sleeping","that's nonsense","I agree with the idea"," yes, I am"],
  correct_option: "I agree with the idea",
  explanation: `The option "I agree with the idea" is an appropriate completion for Mother's response because it demonstrates her agreement with Father's statement about the importance of family members respecting each other.`
},
{
  id:47,
  question: " Ararsa:_________ \n Melaku: Hawa: I always wash my face.",
  options: ["How do you keep your personal hygiene?"," What is personal hygiene?"," Where do you wash your clothes?"," Where do you wash your clothes?"],
  correct_option: "How do you keep your personal hygiene?",
  explanation: `Ararsa's question "How do you keep your personal hygiene?" is the most suitable option because it directly pertains to the topic of personal cleanliness, which is implied by Hawa's statement about washing her face.`,
},
{
  id:48,
  question: " Daughter: Mom, which one you chose from these two? \n Mother:____________",
  options: ["  I think you are interested in colors.","I chose the red one because it is stronger than the blue."," In addition, I like black and yellow colors."," You liked the red color when you were a child."],
  correct_option: "I chose the red one because it is stronger than the blue.",
  explanation:  `The option "I chose the red one because it is stronger than the blue" is the most appropriate completion for Mother's response because it directly addresses the daughter's question and provides a clear rationale for Mother's decision.`
},
{
  id:49,
  Question: " Man: What does your uncle do for living? \n Boy:________________________",
  options: ["He is in a bank"," He works very hard in the farm"," He lives in Addis","He is a farmer"],
  correct_option: "He is a farmer",
  explanation:  `The option "He is a farmer" is the most appropriate completion for the boy's response because it directly answers the man's question about the boy's uncle's occupation.`+
  " It succinctly conveys that the boy's uncle earns a living by working as a farmer."
},
{
id:50,
  question: " Teacher: Have you done your homework? \n  Student: _______________",
  options: ["Yes, I haven't"," No, I have", "Yes, I have"," No, I don't"],
  correct_option: "Yes, I have",
  explanation:`This response indicates that the student has completed their homework, which directly answers the teacher's question. Using the present perfect tense ("have done") correctly conveys that the action of completing the homework occurred in the past and has relevance to the present moment.`
},
{
  id:51,
  question: " Sami: How are you, friend? \n Sara: __________________",
  options: ["My name is Sara.","I am Sara."," How do you do?","I am fine."],
  correct_option: "I am fine.",
  explanation: `This response is a common and polite way to answer the question "How are you?" It indicates that Sara is feeling well or in good spirits. It's a straightforward and friendly response to Sami's greeting.`
},
{ 
  id: "VII",
  header1: "Part IV. Writing \n Section One: Punctuation and Capitalization",
  header2: "Instruction: For item 52-54, choose the sentence with the correct punctuation mark and capitalization.",
},
    {
id: 52,
    options: ["My mom asked me to buy the following fruits orange, mango, banana, and lemon." ,
"My mom asked me to buy the following fruits orange, mango, banana, and lemon",
"My mom asked me to buy the following fruits: orange, mango, banana and lemon",
"My mom asked me to buy the following fruits: orange, mango, banana and lemon"],
  correct_option: "My mom asked me to buy the following fruits: orange, mango, banana and lemon.",
  explanation:"Punctuation is important for clarity and grammatical correctness."+
  ` In this case, the correct format includes a colon after "fruits" and commas between each fruit item in the list.`+ 
  ` Additionally, there should be a comma before the conjunction "and" just before the last item in the list to maintain consistency and readability.`
},
{
  id:53,
    options: ["The ras Dashen is found in Ethiopia.",
"The Ras Dashen is found in Ethiopia.",
"the Ras Dashen is found in Ethiopia.",
" the Ras Dashen is found in ethiopia."],
  correct_option: "The Ras Dashen is found in Ethiopia.",
  explanation: ` "Ethiopia" is capitalized as it is a proper noun and Ras Dashen also capitalized. The article "The" is capitalized as well. Overall, this option follows proper capitalization and punctuation rules for English sentences.`
},
{
  id:54,
    options: ["It was difficult to recognize you at first,",
"It was difficult to recognize you at first;",
"it was difficult to recognize you at first.",
" It was difficult to recognize you at first "],
correct_option: "It was difficult to recognize you at first.",
explanation: `This option correctly begins the sentence with a capital letter "It" and ends the sentence with a comma "," to indicate a pause. Additionally, the sentence is correctly punctuated, and "It" is capitalized as it is the beginning of a sentence.`+
 "Therefore, this option adheres to the standard conventions of sentence structure and punctuation in English."
},
{ 
  id: "VIII",
  header1: "Section Two: Reorganizing Jumbled Words",
  header2: "Instruction: for items 55-57, reorganize the jumbled words to make a meaningful sentence.",
},

{
  id:55,
  question: 'sister/in/my/a/older/private/school/learns',
  options: ["My older sister in a school learns private.",
  "My older sister learns in a private school.", 
"My older sister learns a private in school.",
"My older sister learns a school in private."],
correct_option: "My older sister learns in a private school.",
explanation: `This option arranges the words in a grammatically correct order and maintains the clarity of the sentence. It correctly places the subject "My older sister" at the beginning of the sentence, followed by the verb "learns," and then provides additional information about the location by stating "in a private school."`+
` "This structure follows standard English word order and effectively communicates the intended meaning."`
},
{
  id:56,
  question: "is/her/ closing/ why/ she/ eyes?",
  options: ["Why she is closing her eyes?",
 "Why closing she is her eyes?", "Why her eyes she is closing?", "Why is she closing her eyes?"],
 correct_option: "Why is she closing her eyes?"
   },
{
id:57,
question: "you doing/are/your/ examination/now",
options: ["You are doing the examination now?", 
"Are you doing your examination now?", 
"Doing you are examination your?", 
"Your doing examination are you?"],
correct_option: "Are you doing your examination now?"
 },
  { 
      id: "IIX",
      header1: "Three: Reorganizing Jumbled Sentences",
      header2: "Instruction: For item 58, read the following jumbled sentences carefully and choose the appropriate order of the sentences to make a coherent paragraph.",
    },
{    
id:58,
question: "A. Dallol is found in Afar region of Ethiopia. \n" +
"B. Its temperatures can reach as high as 145Â°C in the sun. \n" +
"C. It is one of the lowest and hottest areas of the world. \n" +
"D. This makes the place very difficult for wildlife to live. ",
options: [ "C D B A ","A C B D", "C A D B","B C D A"],
correct_option: "A C B D"
 },
{
 id: 59,
 options: ["Expensiv",
       "Expenssive", 
"Expensve",
"Expensive"],
correct_option:  "Expensive"
},
{
id: 60,
options: ["Believe",
"Believ",
"Beleive",
"Belive"],
correct_option: "Believe"
 }
]